
export const microbiologyChapter5Data = {
  name: "Chapter 5: Basic concepts of mycology",
  mcqs: {
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Which of the following statement is NOT correct regarding yeasts?",
        options: [
          "These are unicellular fungi that do not produce germ tubes or pseudo-hyphae",
          "They reproduce by budding",
          "Filamentous (hyphae-like) structures are seen in tissues or in culture",
          "In culture, the colonies are pasty, resembling bacterial colonies"
        ],
        answer: "c"
      },
      {
        question: "The cytoplasmic membrane of fungi contains",
        options: [
          "Carbohydrate",
          "Protein",
          "Sterol",
          "Mannan"
        ],
        answer: "c"
      },
      {
        question: "The rigidity of fungal cell walls is due to presence of:",
        options: [
          "Protein",
          "Chitin",
          "Teichoic acid",
          "Lipopolysaccharide"
        ],
        answer: "b"
      },
      {
        question: "Which of the following is a subcutaneous mycosis?",
        options: [
          "Favus",
          "Pityriasis versicolor",
          "Tinea capitis",
          "Chromomycosis"
        ],
        answer: "d"
      },
      {
        question: "Which of the following is a superficial fungal infection?",
        options: [
          "Favus",
          "Pityriasis versicolor",
          "Tinea capitis",
          "Chromomycosis"
        ],
        answer: "b"
      },
      {
        question: "Which one of the following fungi is NOT a mould?",
        options: [
          "Rhizopus",
          "Cryptococcus",
          "Aspergillus",
          "Penicillium"
        ],
        answer: "b"
      },
      {
        question: "Which of the following is the morphological characteristic that refers to fungi imperfecti?",
        options: [
          "Lack of cell wall",
          "Lack of septate hyphae",
          "Unidentified sexual phases",
          "Unidentified microconidia"
        ],
        answer: "c"
      },
      {
        question: "Which of the following is NOT a fungal stain?",
        options: [
          "Leishman",
          "Calcofluor white",
          "Periodic acid Schiff",
          "Gomori's methenamine silver"
        ],
        answer: "a"
      },
      {
        question: "All the following media are used for identifying fungi EXCEPT:",
        options: [
          "Cornmeal",
          "Czapek–Dox medium",
          "Bird seed",
          "Horse serum agar"
        ],
        answer: "d"
      },
      {
        question: "The function of cycloheximide in Sabouraud dextrose agar is to prevent the growth of which of the following contaminants:",
        options: [
          "Gram-positive bacteria",
          "Gram-negative bacteria",
          "Moulds",
          "Yeasts"
        ],
        answer: "c"
      },
      {
        question: "Which of the following is correct regarding Sabouraud dextrose agar?",
        options: [
          "Yeast do not grow on this medium.",
          "It has a high concentration of either glucose or maltose",
          "The pH of the medium is high (8.4)",
          "It is prepared in petri dishes"
        ],
        answer: "b"
      },
      {
        question: "The most common direct microscopy method to visualise fungal elements from clinical samples is:",
        options: [
          "KOH preparation",
          "LPCB staining",
          "Iodine mount",
          "Albert stain"
        ],
        answer: "a"
      },
      {
        question: "Yeasts can be identified based on carbohydrate fermentation tests. Which of the following is correct regarding fermentation test?",
        options: [
          "Fermentation test is performed in a medium containing 10% yeast extract and 2% test carbohydrate in distilled water",
          "Fermentation test is performed in a medium containing 10% yeast extract and 2% test carbohydrate in thioglycolate broth",
          "Fermentation test is performed in a medium containing 1% yeast extract and 20% test carbohydrate in distilled water",
          "Fermentation test is performed in a medium containing 1% yeast extract and 2% test carbohydrate in distilled water"
        ],
        answer: "d"
      },
      {
        question: "Which of the following is not a medium to cultivate fungi from clinical samples?",
        options: [
          "Czapek–Dox medium",
          "Bird seed agar",
          "MacConkey's agar",
          "Brain–heart infusion agar"
        ],
        answer: "c"
      },
      {
        question: "Which of the following is NOT a prerequisite for the growth of fungi in the laboratory?",
        options: [
          "Most fungi are grown at a low pH (5.4–6)",
          "All fungi require oxygen for growth",
          "Fungi grow best at 50°C",
          "They are usually incubated in biochemical oxygen demand (BOD) incubators"
        ],
        answer: "c"
      },
      {
        question: "Which stain can be used to visualise fungi from culture?",
        options: [
          "Lactophenol cotton blue",
          "KOH",
          "ZN stain",
          "Methenamine silver stain"
        ],
        answer: "a"
      },
      {
        question: "Which stain can be used to visualise fungi from tissues?",
        options: [
          "Lactophenol cotton blue",
          "KOH",
          "ZN stain",
          "Methenamine silver stain"
        ],
        answer: "d"
      },
      {
        question: "Reynolds-Braude phenomenon refers to the formation of:",
        options: [
          "Chlamydospores",
          "Germ tubes",
          "Rhizoids",
          "Chains of conidia"
        ],
        answer: "b"
      },
      {
        question: "Which of the following fungus is capsulated?",
        options: [
          "Candida",
          "Rhodotorula",
          "Pneumocystis",
          "Cryptococcus"
        ],
        answer: "d"
      },
      {
        question: "Which statement is NOT TRUE regarding Cryptococcus neoformans?",
        options: [
          "Grows at 37°C",
          "Grows on SDA",
          "Possesses polysaccharide capsule",
          "Negative urease test"
        ],
        answer: "d"
      }
    ]
  }
};
